Margaret Goddard Holt Papers, 1814-2004 (bulk 1960-2000)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Holt, Margaret
    - Friends and acquaintances
      - Speight, Francis 1934-36 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Speight, Sarah Blakeslee
        - Outgoing (primarily photocopies)
          - 1930s-40s (Box 24, Folder 14)
          - 1950s-1997, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Incoming 1934-43, 1977-99, undated, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
        - Biographical information and related correspondence about Sarah Blakeslee Speight and Francis Speight 1985-2002 (Box 25, Folder 4)
        - Sketch of Margaret Holt by Francis Speight 1932, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 25)
      - Stegemann, Jane 1978-99, [see also "Letters which in some way help..."] (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Weyl family (Box 25)
        - Carr, Annemarie Weyl (daughter of Martha T. Weyl) (Box 25)
          - Outgoing 2000, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
          - Incoming 1996-2003 (Box 25, Folder 7)
        - Weyl, Martha Thompson (Box 25)
          - Outgoing (includes Lee E. Holt correspondence) (Box 25)
            - 1977-94, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 8-11)
            - 1995-2001, undated (Box 26, Folder 1-4)
          - Incoming 1986-2001, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
        - Weyl/Holt third party 1996-2001, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Zaret, Lillian 1983-84, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Other friends (Box 26)
        - Outgoing 1917-2003, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Incoming (Box 27)
          - 1927-94 (Box 27, Folder 2-10)
          - 1995-2003, undated, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - "Letters which in some way help make MGH feels [sic] as if her life hasn't been wasted..." (Box 28)
      - Family 1983-93, [see also correspondence of individual family members] (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Bentley, Rabbi Philip J. 1992-93 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - O'Connor, Dee 1992-93, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Stegemann, Jane 1990-97, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Others 1953-98, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Death row inmates (Box 28)
      - Abu-Jamal, Mumia: third party 1995-96, [see also SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES - Death penalty] (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Barley, Nathaniel
        - Outgoingcirca 1996-2000 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - Incoming
          - Jul 1994-Jun 1996 (Box 29, Folder 3-6)
          - Jul 1996-Jan 2000, undated (Box 30, Folder 1-7)
        - Third party 1995-2003 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Biographical information: funeral5 Feb 2000 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Legal defense
          - Correspondence, clippings, and statements 1995-99 (Box 30, Folder 10)
          - Court documentscirca 1997-98 (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Bennett, Baby Ray
        - Outgoing, third party, and receipts 1999-2001, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Incoming 1993-2003, undated (Box 31, Folder 2-6)
      - Brown, Linda
        - 1998-Jun 2001 (Box 31, Folder 7-8)
        - Jul 2001-2002, undated (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
      - Graham, Gary
        - Correspondence 1993, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 4)
        - Gary Graham Legal Defense Committee: memoranda and publications 1991, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Hopkins, Bobby Ray 2000 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Lavasseur, Raymond Luc 1999-2003 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Webb, Freddie Lee, Jr.
        - Incoming 1993-94, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
        - Letters to Margaret Holt, 1992-1994: pamphlet, notes, and related correspondence1995, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 9)
        - Third party 1993-94 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence and notes: re: the death penalty and other death row prisoners 1993-2000, [see also SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES - Death penalty] (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Editors
      - 1960s-2003, undated (Box 33, Folder 1-7)
      - Compilation: binder 2003 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Re: editorials by others 2001-03 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Officials and elected representatives
      - Local: Amherst, Massachusetts and environs 1992, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - State: Massachusetts and Texas 1982-2002 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - National
        - Presidents 1979-98 (Box 33, Folder 12)
        - Secretaries of State and Interior 1980-93 (Box 33, Folder 13)
        - House of Representatives 1979-96 (Box 33, Folder 14)
        - Senate 1970-2002 (Box 33, Folder 15)
        - Judges and Supreme Court Justices 1969-99 (Box 33, Folder 16)
        - Other 2002 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - International 1984-92 (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - Other: human rights, death penalty, prisoners' rights, and Middle East peace 1978-2004 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Other family members
    - Goddard, Fanny Reed
      - Outgoing
        - Holt, Alison and Geoffrey 1943-44, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Holt, Daisy Cone 1938 (Lee E. Holt's mother) (Box 34, Folder 2)
        - Holt, Lee Elbert 1937-48, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
        - Holt, Margaret G. 1930-49, undated (Box 34, Folder 4-13)
        - Holt, Margaret G. and Lee E. 1939-49, undated (Box 34, Folder 14-16)
        - Worthen, Eleanor G. 1928, undated (Box 34, Folder 17)
        - Other: Dr. Bowie 1949 (Box 34, Folder 18)
      - Incoming 1906-48 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Goddard, Florence 1892-1955, undated (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Goddard, Harold Clarke
      - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield 1944-49, 1981 (includes some correspondence with Margaret and Lee E. Holt) (Box 34, Folder 21)
      - Goddard, Fanny Reed 1904-48 (Box 34, Folder 22)
      - Goddard, Mary Clarke 1893-1903, undated (Box 34, Folder 23)
      - Holt, Alisoncirca 1948 (Box 34, Folder 24)
      - Holt, Daisy Cone 1937 (Box 34, Folder 25)
      - Holt, Geoffrey 1941-46, undated (Box 34, Folder 26)
      - Holt, Lee E. 1936-49, undated (Box 34, Folder 27-28)
      - Holt, Margaret 1922-49, undated (Box 35, Folder 1-9)
      - Holt, Margaret and Eleanor Worthen 1933-49 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Holt, Margaret and Lee E. 1939-49, undated (Box 35, Folder 11-13)
      - Worthen, Eleanor G. 1928-36 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Others 1897-1949, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Holt, Alison 1946-2001, undated (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
    - Holt, Daisy
      - Holt, Lee Elbert
        - 1926-38 (Box 36, Folder 1-9)
        - 1939, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
        - Fragmentsundated (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Holt, Margaret G. 1937 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Holt, Florence 1922-28, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Holt, Geoffrey 1943-98, undated (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
    - Holt, Helen 1930-39, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Holt, Lee Cone
      - Holt, Alison 1962, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Holt, Geoffrey 1952 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Holt, Lee Elbert (Box 37)
        - 1921-42 (Box 37, Folder 12-20)
        - 1943-57, undated (Box 38, Folder 1-8)
      - Holt, Margaret 1939-41 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Holt, Lee Elbert
      - Family
        - Goddard, Fanny R. and Harold C. 1934-48, undated (Box 38, Folder 10-11)
        - Holt family (parents and sisters)
          - 1924-28 (Box 38, Folder 12-17)
          - 1929-39 (Box 39, Folder 1-12)
        - Holt, Margaret G.
          - Sep 1934 - Dec 1935 (Box 39, Folder 13-18)
          - Jan 1936 - Oct 1937 (Box 40, Folder 1-12)
          - Nov 1937 - Sep 1945 (Box 41, Folder 1-17)
          - Jun 1946 - Dec 1977, undated (Box 42, Folder 1-7)
        - Uretz, Violet Fogle
          - Outgoing 1928-34 (Box 42, Folder 8-9)
          - Incoming 1928-2000 (Box 42, Folder 10-12)
        - Worthen, Eleanor and Mark 1962-82 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Friends and acquaintances
        - Bloomfield, Morton 1938-66 (Box 42, Folder 14)
        - Carpenter, Ford 1931-35 (Box 42, Folder 15)
        - Edward ? 1930, undated (Box 42, Folder 16)
        - Elkisch, Paula 1955-77 (Box 42, Folder 17)
        - Passmien, Richard 1936-39 (Box 42, Folder 18)
        - Other 1925-2003 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Political and professional
        - Academic appointments 1936-59 (Box 43, Folder 2)
        - Letters to the editor 1965-95 (Box 43, Folder 3)
        - U.S. Navy Underwater Sound Lab 1945-51 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Orr, Marylee 1986-2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Orr, Matt 2000 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Poskas, Sara 1986-2002, n.d (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Reed, Lewis 1895-1916, undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Walker, Florence Hammersly: Eleanor G. Worthen and Margaret G. Holt 1952-53, undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Worthen, Eleanor Goddard, [see also Margaret Goddard Holt correspondence]
      - Goddard, Fanny R. and Harold C. 1933-40 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - Holt, Lee and Margaret 1933-99, undated (Box 43, Folder 11-14)
      - Letter to the editor 1962 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Worthen, Hilary and Kathy Weingarten 1967-2003 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Worthen, Holly 1986-2003 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified relatives of Lee E. Holt
      - Dick 1934-36 (Box 43, Folder 18)
      - Dorothy 1933-34 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Howard 1934-36 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Uncle Will 1932-33 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Other 1920-36, undated, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous 1868-75, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS
  - Holt, Margaret Goddard
    - Diaries, [see also SERIES V: ARTWORK - notebooks and sketchbooks]
      [closed until Jan. 1, 2028]
      - "Introduction to Journals of Margaret Holt 1975-1976" (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - 1926 (Box 44)
      - Continuous diary 1399 pages
        - 18 Oct 1930-15 Apr 1938 (pp.1-558) (Box 44, Folder 7-21)
        - 26 Apr 1938-24 Feb 1949 (pp. 559-1399) (Box 45, Folder 1-16)
      - Loose pagescirca 1924-36, undated, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - Marriage to Lee E. Holt12 Aug 1939 (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Living in Madison, Wisconsin while Lee earns Ph.D. 1940 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Children (Alison and Geoffrey) 1942-43, 1947 (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - 1932-67 (line diaries) (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
      - Mar 1949 - Feb 1961 (notebooks) (Box 47, Folder 1-14)
      - Feb 1961 - Feb 1981 (notebooks) (Box 48, Folder 1-12)
      - 1981-90 (notebooks) (Box 49, Folder 1-7)
      - 1990-2003, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-8)
      - undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Fragmentsundated (Box 51, Folder 2-4)
      - Dreams 1936-51, 2003 (?), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 5-10)
    - Travel diaries, [see also SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS]
      - American Southwest 1972-73 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Europe
        - Sep 1974 - Feb 1975 (Box 51, Folder 12-13)
        - Feb - Jul 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
        - Mar - Sep 1979 (Box 52, Folder 4)
        - Typescripts
          - DiariesSep 1974 - Jul 1975, undated
            - Copy 1 (Box 52, Folder 5-7)
            - Copy 2 (Box 52, Folder 8-9)
            - Copy 3 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
            - Fragments (Box 53, Folder 3-7)
          - Diaries 1979, undated
            - Copy 1 (Box 53, Folder 8-9)
            - Copy 2 (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
            - Fragment (Box 54, Folder 3)
            - Editorial comments by "Jane" 1979 (Box 54, Folder 4)
          - Diaries1981, undated (Box 54, Folder 5-7)
    - Travel writings
      - "Weeds and Wanderings": typescripts circa 1984
        - Copy 1 (Box 54, Folder 8-9)
        - Copy 2 (Box 54, Folder 10-11)
        - Copy 3 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
        - Copy 4 (illustrated)
          - Pages 1-154 (incomplete) (Box 55, Folder 3-4)
          - Pages 1-150 (incomplete) (Box 55, Folder 5)
          - Photocopy, pages 1-147 (incomplete) (Box 55, Folder 6)
        - Fragments (Box 55, Folder 7)
        - Draft of introduction (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Short stories
      - "A Story for Gee": draftundated (illustrated) (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - "The White Colt": typescript 1940 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Essays
      - Amherst Disarmament Coalition: testimony 1983 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Berrigan, Philipundated (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Earnshaw, Marion: eulogyundated (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - "Wealth": draft and typescript 1940 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Untitledundated (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Other 1927-2003, undated (Box 56, Folder 7-8)
    - Poems, [see also Oversize Box 107]
      - "Old Age" 1996-98 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - "Security" circa 1998 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - "Silver Birds and Other Poems" 1920 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - "Thoughts For Survival" 2001 (Box 56, Folder 12)
      - Othercirca 1926-2003, undated, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 56, Folder 13)
      - "Margaret Holt's Poems and Drawings": photocopies 1998 (Box 56, Folder 14)
      - Poems by Margaret Holt (volume), by Margaret Holt and Eleanor Holt (notebook), and by others 1929-2000, undated (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - "Klein und Wagner" by Herman Hesse, translated by Manfred Halberstadt and Margaret Holt: typescript and related correspondence 1942, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, and unidentified fragmentsundated (Box 56, Folder 17-18)
  - Other family members
    - Goddard, Harold Clarke
      - Articles 1909-49 (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
      - Books
        - Alphabet of the Imagination 1974
          - Correspondence and reviews (Box 57, Folder 3)
          - Published copy 1974 (unfoldered) (Box 57)
        - The Meaning of Shakespeare 1951
          - Contracts and permissions to quote (Box 57, Folder 4)
          - Correspondence (Box 57, Folder 5)
          - Press releases and reviews (Box 57, Folder 6)
        - Morale: The Mainspring of Victory: published copy (unfoldered) 1916 (Box 57)
        - Studies in New England Transcendentalism: published copy 1908 (Box 57)
        - W. H. Hudson: Bird-Man (1928): published copies1974 (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Diaries and notebooks 1916-50, undated (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
      - Essays and lectures
        - Atomic Peace: pamphlet and correspondence 1950 (Box 58, Folder 3)
        - "Branches of Man: Is the Human Species Subdividing?" undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
        - Other essay and lectures 1918-48, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - Plays 1911-14, undated (Box 58, Folder 6-8)
      - Poetry
        - Poem about Margaret Holt as a child, and poems written for Margaret and Eleanor as children undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
        - Other poemsundated (Box 58, Folder 10)
        - Other poemsundated (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence about writings 1918-71 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Holt, Helen: Winged Glory 1935 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Holt, Lee Elbert (Box 59)
      - Childhood writingscirca 1920-22 (Box 59, Folder 5-8)
      - Diaries
        - 1918-39 (Box 59, Folder 9-13)
        - 1939-93, undated (Box 60, Folder 1-12)
      - Dissertation: "Critical Opinion Concerning the Work of Samuel Butler"
        - Bound copy 1940 (unfoldered) (Box 61)
        - Correspondence re: article and proposed book
          - Trilling, Lionel 1944-49 (Box 61, Folder 1)
          - Other 1943-50 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Der Grune Heinrich by Gottfried Keller: translation and proposed publication, and related correspondence 1943-44 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Essays (Box 61)
      - Academic
        - Samuel Butler 1935, undated (Box 61, Folder 4-5)
        - Other topics 1933-61, undated (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Professional: "The German Use of Sonic Listening," Journal of the Acoustical Society of America Jul 1947 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Personal 1994, undated (Box 61, Folder 8-11)
      - Speechesundated (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Writings by others 1987-91 (Box 61, Folder 13)
- SERIES IV. ACTIVISM, [see also SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES]
  - Anthrax research protest (University of Massachusetts at Amherst)
    - Correspondence and statements by Margaret Holt 1989-90 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Legal documents and articles about legal defense 1988-90 (Box 62, Folder 2-4)
    - Notescirca 1988-90 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, fliers, and petition 1988-90, undated (Box 62, Folder 6-7)
  - Gray Panthers, [see also Vigils]
    - Correspondence and notes 1987-93, undated (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, articles, and fliers 1983-94, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Newsletters and reports 1982-99, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Intergenerational Information Center (Amherst, Massachusetts): chronology and notescirca 1990 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Agendas and minutes 1986-89 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Healthcare initiatives: clippings, articles, and conference materials 1988-91, undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Vigils, [see also Gray Panthers, Oversize Materials, and SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS]
    - Leaflets and posters compiled for distribution
      - 1967-88 (Box 63, Folder 6-9)
      - 1989-99 (Box 64, Folder 1-7)
      - 2000-04, undated (Box 65, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence, clippings, fliers, notes, and permit application 1964-2003 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Videocassettes: 10th and 21st anniversary vigils16 Jul 1989, 16 Jul 2000, [DVD copy available for research use] (Box 66)
    - T-shirt with photograph of Margaret and Lee E. Holtundated (Box 66)
  - Memorabilia: political buttons (Box 67)
- SERIES V. ARTWORK
  - Writings
    - By Margaret G. Holt: typescriptundated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - By others: clippings, and exhibit brochures 1948-2004, undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Conservation
    - Barbara Wocjik (conservator of paintings): correspondence, reports, slides, and invoices 2000-04 (Box 68, Folder 3-5)
    - Williamstown Art Conservation Center: correspondence, reports, slides, and invoices 2001 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Transparenciescirca 1977-92 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Drawings and paintings, [see also Oversize Boxes 109-112]
    - Childhood drawings: drawings and list 1920-25 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Animals
      - Drawings and paintings 1941-62, undated (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Bas relief wood carving of a calfundated (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Botanicals
      - Apple projectundated (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - General 1974-78, undated (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Landscapes 1940-74, undated (Box 68, Folder 13-14)
    - People 1934-94, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Still lifes 1953, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Collage of envelopes with fish designundated, [see Oversize Box 108] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sketchbooks 1929-1990s, n.d, [see also Oversize Box 110] (Box 69-80)
  - Copy photographs and transparenciesundated (Box 81)
  - Artwork by others, [see Oversize Box 108] (Box 81)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Daguerreotypes: Goddard and Reed families, and unidentifiedundated (Box 82)
  - Holt, Margaret Goddard
    - Alone 1913-2003, undated (Box 83, Folder 1-6)
    - With Lee E. Holt 1939-2003, undated (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - 80th and 92nd birthday parties 1991, 2003, [see also Oversize Materials Box 113] (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - With familycirca 1917-1998 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - With friendscirca 1940s-2000s (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - While traveling: United States
      - Circa 1970-94 (Box 84, Folder 1-2)
      - With Lee E. Holt and friendscirca 1970-2000 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Vigils and demonstrations
    - Amherst vigil
      - Margaret Holt 1955-2003 (includes Lee E. Holt and Frances Crowe) (Box 84, Folder 4-5)
      - Margaret Holt, by Diana Jo Davies and Kady 2002, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 84, Folder 6)
      - Photograph album pages 1967-2000s (Box 84, Folder 7-8)
    - Other 1960s-2003 (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Family members
    - Goddard, Fanny Reed, and Reed family 1899-1936, undated (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Goddard, Harold Clarke, and Goddard family 1881-1943, undated (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Holt, Alison, and Geoffrey L. Holtcirca 1943-2002 (Box 85, Folder 1-3)
    - Holt, Lee
      - Alone and in groups 1912-2003, undated, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - With family 1914-17, undated (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Cone, Daisy with Lee, and Florence and Helen Cone 1920-55, undated (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Worthen, Eleanor Goddard and familycirca 1930s-1998, undated (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Friendscirca 1940s-2003 (includes Maggie Kuhn, Philip Berrigan, and prison inmates) (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Homes and vacation campsitesundated (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Pets and unidentified photographsundated (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies
    - Holt, Margaret (Box 86)
      - Alone and with others 1930s-90s (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - Traveling 1960s-90s (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Holt, Lee 1940s-69, [see also Oversize Box 107] (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Holt, Alison and Geoffrey L. Holtcirca 1942-90s (Box 86, Folder 6-8)
    - Pets and family homescirca 1936s-90s (Box 86, Folder 9)
- SERIES VII. SUBJECT FILES
  - Affordable housing and homelessness 1985-90, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
  - Animals and animal rights 1993-95 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Art, poetry, and theater 1986-92, undated (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Authors
    - Blake, Williamundated (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Shakespeare, William 1967 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Childcare and children's rights 1990-2001 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Civil rights, [see also Racism]
    - Generalcirca 1964-2002 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - American Civil Liberties Union 1990-91, undated (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Amnesty International 1987-89, undated (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - King, Martin Luther 1960s-90s (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People 1985-98 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - Countries
    - Africa 1978-2000, undated (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Caribbean and Latin America
      - Cuba 1997, undated (Box 87, Folder 13)
      - Granada 1984 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Central America
      - General 1983-91, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 87, Folder 15)
      - El Salvador 1983-98, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 87, Folder 16)
      - El Salvador 1983-98, undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Guatemala 1990-2002, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Honduras 1984-89, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Nicaragua 1983-91, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 88, Folder 4-5)
      - Panama 1990, undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - China 1961, 1997 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Middle East
      - Ahmad, Eqbal 1983-91, undated (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Articles, newsletters and published materials
        - "New England Briefs for Middle East Peacework" 1977-83 (Box 88, Folder 9-10)
        - Others 1972-88 (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Egyptcirca 1981, undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Iran 1978-81 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Iraq
        - Gulf War 1990-92, undated, [see also Oversize Box 123] (Box 89, Folder 3-6)
        - Sanctionscirca 1990-98 (Box 89, Folder 7)
        - Clinton era 1998 (Box 89, Folder 8)
        - Iraq War 2002-03, undated (Box 89, Folder 9)
      - Israel (Arab-Israeli conflict)
        - Organizations and publications
          - American Near East Refugee Aid 1984-91 (Box 89, Folder 10)
          - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee 1988-2002 (Box 90, Folder 1)
          - Americans for Peace Now 1990-98 (Box 90, Folder 2)
          - Arab-American Institute 1987-97 (Box 90, Folder 3-4)
          - Breaking the Siege 1989-95 (Box 90, Folder 5)
          - Council for the National Interest 1990-92 (Box 90, Folder 6)
          - I & P: Israel & Palestinian Political Report
            - 1984-88 (Box 90, Folder 7)
            - 1990-94 (Box 90, Folder 8)
          - Jerusalem: A Crisis in the Makingundated (Box 90, Folder 9)
          - Jerusalem Monitor 1997-2000 (Box 90, Folder 10)
          - The Jewish Guardian 1982-87 (Box 90, Folder 11)
          - Jewish Peace Lobby 1993-97 (Box 90, Folder 12)
          - The Link 1991-98 (Box 91, Folder 1)
          - Middle East Children's Alliance 1992-94 (Box 91, Folder 2)
          - National Association of Arab Americans 1983-97 (Box 91, Folder 4)
          - The Other Israel 1988-98 (Box 91, Folder 5)
          - Palestinian Human Rights Information Center 1990-93 (Box 91, Folder 6)